Basically, there's a major demographic event going on.
في الأساس ، هناك حدث ديموغرافي رئيسي يحدث الآن
And it may be that passing the 50 percent urban point
ويمكن أن تعبر نسبة ال 50 في المئة في المناطق الحضرية
is an economic tipping point. So the world now is a map of connectivity.
التي تمثل نقطة تحول اقتصادي. اذا العالم الآن هو خريطة من التواصل
It used to be that Paris and London and New York were the largest cities.
لقد كانت باريس ولندن ونيويورك أكبر المدن
What we have now is the end of the rise of the West. That's over.
ما لدينا الآن هو نهاية صعود الغرب. أنتهى ذلك
The aggregate numbers are overwhelming.
إجمالي الأعداد هائل
So what's really going on? Well, villages of the world are emptying out.
اذا ما الذي يجري فعلياً؟ حسناً، قرى العالم تخلو الآن
The question is, why?
السؤال هو، لماذا؟
And here's the unromantic truth -- and the city air makes you free,
وهذه هي الحقيقة غير الرومانسية-- وهواء المدينة يجعلك حُراً
they said in Renaissance Germany. So some people go to places
قالوا في ألمانيا الناهضة. حتى أن بعض الناس يذهبون إلى أماكن
like Shanghai but most go to the squatter cities where aesthetics rule.
مثل شنغهاي، لكن معظمهم يذهبون الى مدن عشوائية حيث يحكم الجمال
And these are not really a people oppressed by poverty.
وهؤلاء ليسو أناس فعلاً مقهورين من الفقر
They're people getting out of poverty as fast as they can.
أنهم أناس يخرجون من الفقر بأسرع ما يستطيعون
They're the dominant builders and to a large extent, the dominant designers.
أنهم غالبية البناة والى حد كبير، غالبية المصممين
They have home-brewed infrastructure and vibrant urban life.
لديهم بنية تحتية مصنعة منزليا وحياة حضرية حيوية
One-sixth of the GDP in India is coming out of Mumbai.
سدس الناتج المحلي الإجمالي في الهند يأتي من بومباي
They are constantly upgrading, and in a few cases, the government helps.
أنهم يطورون بصورة مستمرة، وفي حالات قليلة، تساعدهم الحكومة
Education is the main event that can happen in cities.
التعليم هو الحدث الرئيسي الذي يحصل في المدن
What's going on in the street in Mumbai?
ماذا يحدث في الشوارع الرئيسية لمومباي؟
Al Gore knows. It's basically everything.
آل غور يعرف. في الحقيقة يحدث كل شئ
There's no unemployment in squatter cities. Everyone works.
لا يوجد بطالة في المدن العشوائية. الجميع يعمل
One-sixth of humanity is there. It's soon going to be more than that.
سدس البشرية هناك. وقريباً ستكون أكثر من ذلك
So here's the first punch line:
ولذا فأن هذه هي أول لكمة
cities have defused the population bomb.
نزعت المدن فتيل القنبلة السكانية
And here's the second punch line.
وهنا هي ثاني لكمة
That's the news from downtown. Here it is in perspective.
هذه الأنباء من وسط المدينة. هنا في وجهات النظر
Stars have shined down on earth's life for billions of years.
لمعت النجوم على حياة الأرض لبلايين السنين
Now we're shining right back up.
الآن نحن نلمع بالعكس.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم